Okay, so let's look at how we can implement this function.
现在我们来看看要如何实现这个函数
It accepts a parameter which is an array of strings called
它接受了一个参数 也就是一个叫 names 的字符串数组
'names' and returns a string which has the longest name found in that array.
并返回一个字符串 也就是函数在数组中找到的最长名称
The first thing we want to do is we want to calculate
首先我们要计算数组的长度
the length of our array and store it into a variable size,
并将长度赋值给变量 size
so that we know how many cells exist in this array;
这样我们就能知道数组里有多少个元素了
and then hence, build our loop based on that.
然后 基于这一点创建循环
The second thing we want to do is initialize a variable called
我们要做的第二件事是初始化变量 longestName
'longestName' or whatever that would store the longest name we've found so far.
我们也能管该变量叫其它名称 反正作用就是存储到目前为止我们找到的最长名称
And we want to initialize it to names of zero,
将该变量初始化为 names [0] 的值
which is the first name in our array.
也就是数组的第一个名称
Then, we want to create our loop that would start from one,
之后 创建循环 使其从 1 开始
which is the very next name after that one,
也就是这之后的下一个名称
and it would keep going just before it reaches the size of the array.
循环计数器在到达数组大小之前 不会停止执行
The increment is just i++ as usual.
增量一如既往为 i++
Inside that loop, we want to compare the length of
在循环里 我们得把数组内每个元素的长度
each cell in that array to the longest name that we've found so far.
与到目前为止我们找到的最长名称的长度进行比较
So we say, if names of i,
所以这么写 if (names [i]
which is the string in that particular cell of the array at the position i;
names [i] 即数组位置 i 上的元素中的字符串
we say if names of i.length,
我们写 if (names [i] . length
so we're measuring the length of that particular string;
也就是我们要衡量出相应字符串的长度
and we're comparing it to the longestName.length,
将其与 longestName.length 进行比较
which should be storing the longest name we found so far.
而 longestName.length 存放的是到目前为止我们找到的最长名称
So if that name dot length is actually larger than the longestName.length,
所以如果 name .length 大于 longestName.length
then we update the longest name to be that name.
那么就把 longestName 更新为该名称
It's very similar to finding the smallest number in an array as well,
这很像是在找数组里的最小值
except that we're comparing if it's greater than rather than smaller than.
除了一点 我们是在进行大于的比较 而不是小于
After we're done with our loop,
完成循环后
that means we've visited every single cell in the array and we're
也就意味着我们访问了数组里的每个元素
always updating longestName if we find something that's longer,
而且每当我们找到更长的名称 我们就对 longestName 进行了更新
that means we can safely return longestName. There we go.
于是我们可以安全地返回出 longestName 好了